A Finding Aid to the W.G. Constable Papers, 1905-1983, bulk 1920-1976, in the Archives of American Art AAA.conswmgp
Archives of American Art
- American Defense Harvard Group, 1942-1946; Series 5; 0.6 Linear feet Box 15
  - Ministry of Home Security, London (Webb, Geoffrey), 1944 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - N Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - National Gallery, London (Clark, Kenneth), 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - National Resources Planning Board, Committee on Conservation of Cultural Resources (Leland, Waldo), 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - O-P Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Princeton University, 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Q-R Miscellaneous, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Ross, Marvin C., 1944 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - S-U Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Undset, Sigrid, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - V Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Victoria and Albert Museum (Maclagan, Eric), 1943 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - W-Z Miscellaneous, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Manual, Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Material in the Field (draft), 1943 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Manual, Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Material in the Field (Part I), 1943 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Manual, Safeguarding and Conserving Cultural Material in the Field (Part II), 1943 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Research Notes, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Committee Minutes and Reports, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 35-37)
  - Booklet, War-Time Storage in Wales from the National Gallery, London, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Clippings, 1942-1946 (Box 15, Folder 39-44)
- Office of Military Government for Germany, 1947-1952; Series 6; 0.3 Linear feet Box 15
  Office of Military Government for Germany comprises of materials related to Constable's work surveying the state of German and Italian art institutions after World War II. Correspondence includes memoranda and fact sheets from the U.S. Army to Constable, letters arranging visits to and from German cultural institutions, and updates on the logistics of travel and salary. The series also includes a transcript of a radio interview with Constable in 1949, Constable's notebook "Visits in Germany" (1949), a copy of his report Art and Reorientation: Status and Future of Museums and the Teaching of Art in Western Germany, and additional notes, miscellanous reports, and printed material tangentially related to the project.
  - Correspondence, 1947-1950, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 45-50)
  - Interview Transcript, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Notebook, "Visits in Germany", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Notes, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Report, "Art and Reorientation in Western Germany", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - Report, "Eichkamp", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Report, "Exceptional Return of Works of Art", 1948 (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Report, "Experiences Teaching at the University of Gottingen", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Report, "[Germany] Education and Cultural Relations", 1948 (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - Report, "Monuments, Fine Arts and Archives", 1947 (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - Report, "Our Stake in Germany", 1949 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1948-1949 (Box 15, Folder 61)
- Exhibitions, 1930-1969; Series 7; 1 Linear feet Box 15-16, OV 29
  Correspondence, notes, lists, research material, and reports document exhibitions organized by Constable prior to his employment at and after his retirement from the Boston Museum of Art. There is substanital correspondence related to the traveling Canaletto exhibition (1964) and to the tentatively titled Fakes and Forgeries exhibition, which was researched but not shown due to lack of funding.
  - "Art Owned by Alumni of Harvard Business School" (1965), 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 62-63)
  - "British Art" (1934), 1933 (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - "British Painting" (1938) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "British Painting in the 18th Century" (1957-1958), 1955-1957 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - "Canaletto" (1964), 1962-1965 (Box 16, Folder 4-7)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (correspondence), 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 8-10)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (notes), 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (printed material), 1937-1953 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Fakes and Forgeries (artworks), 1945-1947 (Box 16, Folder 14-20)
  - French Art, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - French 19th Century Paintings, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - "From Ricci to Tiepolo" (1969), 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Italian Art, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - "Mostra del Settecento a Roma" (1959), 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 25-26)
  - "Omega Workshops, 1913-1920" (1964) (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - "Romantic Era: French and British Paintings, 1750-1850" (1965), 1964-1965 (Box 16, Folder 28-31)
  - "Sport and the Horse" (1960) (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - "I Vedutisti Veneziani del Settecento" (1967), 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Oversize Announcements, Omega Workshops, 1964 (Box OV 29)
    Oversized material from Box 16, Folder 27.
- Research Files, 1922-1976; Series 8; 7.5 Linear feet Box 16-24, OV 28-29
  Constable's research files contain notes, lists, correspondence, bibliographic reference cards, and printed and photographic reference material related to research on artists, conservation, collections, collecting, and other topics.
  This series is arranged as 9 subseries:
  8.1: Artists, 1925-1964
  8.2: Artists, Canaletto, 1934-1976
  8.3: Artists, Vedute Painters, 1922-1967
  8.4: Museum Conservation, circa 1940-1960
  8.5: Museums and Galleries, 1930-1965
  8.6: Private Collections, 1930-1964
  8.7: Public Collections, circa 1930-1960
  8.8: Reference Cards, circa 1940-1960
  8.9: Schools of Art, circa 1940-1960
  - Artists, 1925-1964; 8.1
    Materials include notes, lists, correspondence, and printed and photographic reference material related to artists. Substantial material on Carlo Bonavia, John Constable, Thomas Patch, and Giovanni Pannini can be found in this subseries.
    - Dutch Artists, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - English Artists, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - Flemish and Early Dutch Artists, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - French Artists, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - German Artists, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - Italian Artists, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 39-40)
    - Spanish Artists, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - Theatrical Designers, Bibiena Family, circa 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Theatrical Designers, Venice, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bonavia, Carlo, 1948-1963 (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
    - Bottani, Giuseppe, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Claude (Claude Lorrain), circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Constable, John (correspondence), 1955-1963 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Constable, John, Essay, "'The Lock' as a Theme in the Work of John Constable", 1963 (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
    - Constable, John, Photographs of Artwork, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Goupy, Joseph, circa 1960 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Thomas, 1925-1936 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Patch, Thomas, 1927-1964 (Box 17, Folder 14-16)
    - Piero (Piero Della Francesca), 1943 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Pannini, Giovanni Paolo, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 18-20)
    - Ricci, Marco, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Ricci, Sebastino, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Richardon, Jonathan, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Titian, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 3.
    - Wilson, Richard, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Zocchi, Giuseppi, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Oversize Photographs of Artwork, Titian, circa 1940-1960 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 17, Folder 24.
  - Artists, Canaletto, 1934-1976; 8.2
    Materials comprise Constable's book research on the Venetian painter Canaletto. This includes comprehensive lists of public and private collections containing Canaletto's artwork, correspondence regarding specific works of art, biographical research notes, and notes on artistic influences. Printed material and reference photographs of works of art are also found in this sub-series.
    - Additions and Alterations, Canaletto (2nd edition), 1976 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Bibliography and Reference Sources, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Book Reviews, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Collections of Artwork, Drawings, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 30-31)
    - Collections of Artwork, Paintings, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Collections of Artwork at Auction, circa 1940-1960 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Collections of Artwork in Exhibitions, 1955 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    - Collections of Artwork in Europe, circa 1930-1960 (Box 17, Folder 35-39)
    - Collections of Artwork in North America, 1940-1955 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1957 (Box 18, Folder 3-6)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1967 (Box 18, Folder 7-9)
    - Research Notes, Artworks in the School of Canaletto, 1940-1967 (Box 18, Folder 10-12)
    - Research Notes, Artworks Related to Canaletto School, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
    - Research Notes, Artworks Not Included in Book, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
    - Research Notes, Biographical, circa 1930-1960 (Box 18, Folder 17-19)
    - Research Notes, Drawings, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 20-23)
    - Research Notes, Etchings, circa 1930-1960 (Box 18, Folder 24-29)
    - Research Notes, Forgeries and Copies, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Research Notes, Technical Style, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 31-32)
    - Research Notes, English Imitations, 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 33)
    - Research Notes, English Influence, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes, French Influence, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Cityscapes, 15th-16th Century, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Cityscapes, 16th-17th Century, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Cityscapes, 17th Century, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Research Notes, Venetian Influences, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 6-8)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 4.
    - Oversize Photographs of Artwork, Venetian Influence, circa 1940-1960 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 19, Folder 8.
  - Artists, Vedute Painters, 1922-1967; 8.3
    Materials include notes, lists, correspondence, and printed and photographic reference material related to vedute/topographical painters and vedute school followers. Substantial material on Francesco Battaglioli, Luca Carlevaris, Francesco Guardi, Antonio Joli, Samuel Scott, and Francesco Tironi can be found in this subseries.
    - Battaglioli, Francesco, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
    - Bella, Gabriele, 1922-1962 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Borsato, Giuseppe, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Brancaleoni, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Busiri, Giovanni, circa 1960 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Carlevaris, Luca (notes), circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 15-20)
    - Carlevaris, Luca (photographs of artwork), circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 21-25)
    - Cimaroli, Gianbattista, circa 1950 (Box 19, Folder 26-27)
    - Clerisseau, Charles-Louis, 1963 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Costa, Gianfrancesco, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Diziani, Antonio, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Diziani, Gaspari, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Domenichini, Apollonio, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Edwards, Pietro, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 33)
    - Fabris, Jacob, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Fabris, Pietro, 1961-1964 (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Garola, Pietro Francesco, circa 1950-1960 (Box 19, Folder 36)
    - Gaspari Family, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - Gravenbrock Family, circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - Griffier, Robert, circa 1960 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - Guardi, Francesco (private collections), circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 40-41)
    - Guardi, Francesco (forgeries), circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 42)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 5.
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, biographical), circa 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 43-46)
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, biographical), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Guardi, Francesco (photographs of artwork), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, Capricci drawings and landscapes), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 4-6)
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, Capricci ruins), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 7-11)
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, Venice), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 12-13)
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, Venice site specific artworks), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 14-18)
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, Venice site specific artworks), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 19-23)
    - Guardi, Francesco (notes, Venice site specific artworks), circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 24-28)
    - Guardi, Giacomo, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Guardi, Giovanni Antonio, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Jackson, J.B., circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Joli, Antonio, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 32-35)
    - Marlow, William, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Moretti, Giuseppi, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Navone, Francesco, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Panini, Giovanni, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Patch, Thomas, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Richter, Jan, circa 1960 (Box 20, Folder 41)
    - Richter, Johann, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 42)
    - Scalvini, Petrus, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 43)
    - Scott, Samuel, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 44-47)
    - Smith, Joseph, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Stom, Antonio, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Tironi, Francesco, circa 1940-1960 (Box 20, Folder 50-51)
    - Van Link, Hendrick Frans, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Vanvitelli, Gaspar, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 2-5)
    - Zanetti, Antonio, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Topographical Painters, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
    - Notes on Vedute Painters, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 9-11)
    - Notes on Vedute School Followers, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 12-13)
    - Oversize Photographs of Artwork, Guardi, Francesco, circa 1940-1960 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Oversized materials from Box 19, Folder 42 and Box 20, Folders 10, 15, and 21-22.
    - Oversize Photographs of Artwork, Moretti, Giuseppi, circa 1940-1960 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 20, Folder 37.
  - Museum Conservation, circa 1940-1960; 8.4
    Materials consist of notes, reports, articles, and miscellaneous printed and photographic material regarding techniques relevant to museum conservation and curation.
    - Canvas Relining, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Cleaning, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Fading, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Framing and Mounting, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Gallery Display and Storage, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Gallery Lighting, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 20-21)
    - Painting Inspection, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Painting Techniques, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Pastels, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Research Rooms, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Restoration, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Restoration Panals, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Solvents, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - Ventilation Systems, circa 1940-1960 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - Oversize Blueprints, Gallery Display and Storage, circa 1940-1960 (Box OV 29)
      Oversized material from Box 21, Folder 19.
  - Museums and Galleries, 1930-1965; 8.5
    Materials consist of notes, aquisition reports, memoranda, meeting minutes, and photographs of artwork for museums that Constable worked with in an advisory capacity.
    - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, circa 1930-1960 (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1938-1957 (Box 21, Folder 31-32)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa, 1931-1956 (Box 21, Folder 33-36)
    - Walker Art Center, circa 1940s (Box 21, Folder 37-43)
    - Watts Gallery, 1956-1965 (Box 21, Folder 44-46)
    - Oversize Landscape Diagram, Watts Gallery, circa 1958-1964 (Box OV 29)
      Oversized material from Box 21, Folder 46.
  - Private Collections, 1930-1964; 8.6
    Materials include notes, lists, correspondence, and photographs describing artworks owned by private collectors in North America and Europe, with particular emphasis given to American and British collections. The subseries also includes information on works of art handled through dealers and auction houses.
    - American, New England, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - American, California, District of Columiba, Indiana, Michigan, Missouri, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - American, Ohio, New York, Pennsylvania, Virginia, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - American, Virginia (Mellon, Paul), 1959-1964 (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
    - British, A-B Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 9-12)
    - British, C-D Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 13-15)
    - British, Douglas, R. Langton, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - British, E-Le Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 17-22)
    - British, Lee, Lord, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - British, L-P Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 24-27)
    - British, Q-Wi Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 28-30)
    - British, Woburn Abbey, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - British, Wo-Wz, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Canadian, A-Z Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - European, A-Z Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 34-35)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 6.
    - Auction House, Christie's, circa 1930-1960 (Box 22, Folder 36-37)
    - Dealers, Agnew's, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Dealers, Goldsmith's Hall, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Reference Resources, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Catalog, European, A-Z Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1950 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      Oversized material from Box 22, Folder 35.
  - Public Collections, circa 1930-1960; 8.7
    Materials include notes, lists, correspondence, and photographs describing artworks owned by public galleries and museums in North America and Europe, with particular emphasis given to American and British institutions.
    - American, California, Colorado, Indiana, Massachusetts, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - American, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Texas, Wisconsin, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - American, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - British, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - British, Westminster Abbey, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 8-9)
    - British, Winchester School, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Canadian, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - European, circa 1930-1960 (Box 23, Folder 12-16)
  - Reference Cards, circa 1940-1960; 8.8
    Materials consist of note cards referencing bibliographic sources related to Constable's research interests, including the Venetian artist Canaletto, private and public art collections, and European schools of art.
    - Artists, Canaletto, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Private and Public Art Collections, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Schools of Art, European, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Schools of Art, Italy, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Schools of Art, circa 1940-1960; 8.9
    Materials include notes, lists, correspondence, and printed and photographic materials related to styles of European art, with particular emphasis given to genres of English, German, Italian, and Scandinavian art.
    - American Contemporary, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Austrian, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Bohemian, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 24-25)
    - Dutch, circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - English (reference sources), circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - English (medieval), circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - English (14th-19th century), circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 29-32)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 7 and OV 29.
    - English (paintings), circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - English (portraits), circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - English (site specific objects), circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 35-37)
    - English (watercolors), circa 1940-1960 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - English (watercolors), circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - English (miscellaneous), circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Spanish, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Flemish, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - French, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - German, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 7-8)
    - Italian, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 9-11)
    - Scandinavian, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 12-13)
    - Miscellaneous Craft, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Iconography, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Illuminated Manuscripts, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      Oversized material housed in Box 28, Folder 7.
    - Miscellaneous Sculpture, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Oversize Diagram, English (14th-19th century), circa 1940-1960 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Oversized material from Box 23, Folder 29.
    - Oversize Printed Material, English (14th-19th century), circa 1940-1960 (Box OV 29)
      Oversized material from Box 23, Folder 32.
    - Oversize Pamphlet, Miscellaneous Illuminated Manuscripts, circa 1940-1960 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      Oversized material from Box 24, Folder 16.
- Printed Material, 1921-1977; Series 9; 0.5 Linear feet Box 24
  Printed materials include clippings on Constable's work as a museum curator and art historian, as well as articles on miscellaneous art topics; programs; book excerpts and other miscellaneous printed materials.
  - Book Excerpt, [Engravings], 1921 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Book Excerpt, [Miniatures], circa 1920-1930 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Book Excerpt, Ninth Volume of the Walpole Society, 1920-1921 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, Biographical, circa 1925-1977 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1925-1954 (Box 24, Folder 22-26)
  - Clippings, Biographical, 1955-1977 (Box 24, Folder 27-31)
  - Clippings, General Reference, circa 1930-1960 (Box 24, Folder 32-33)
  - Clippings, General Reference, 1927-1961 (Box 24, Folder 34-36)
  - Programs, 1924-1962 (Box 24, Folder 37-40)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1930-1970 (Box 24, Folder 41-44)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1940-1960; Series 10; 1.4 Linear feet Box 24-27, OV 28-29
  Photographic materials include prints of Constable with friends and family. There are also prints, glass negatives and slides of paintings, sculpture and architectural buildings. Photographs and negatives of artwork are assumed to be for research purposes. The series also includes prints of the Fogg Art Museum's interiors and exterior and interior shots of Tennessee Valley Authority dam projects.
  Materials are arranged chronologically within each folder. Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Photographs of W.G. Constable, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of W.G. Constable and Friends, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of W.G. Constable with Works of Art, circa 1940-1960 (Box 24, Folder 47)